<aboutMe>
    <name>Darius</name>
    <role>Developer &amp; Engineer</role>
    <location>Germany - Hamburg</location>
    <currentlyWorkingOn>Portfolio Website</currentlyWorkingOn>
    <hi>Hi, I'm Darius</hi>
    <hero>
        <hi>Hi, I'm Darius</hi>
        <slogan>Code. Hardware. Performance.</slogan>
        <subline>Full-stack Web &amp; Java developer – I create efficient, scalable, and
            maintainable applications for the web and desktop.</subline>
    </hero>
    <whatIAm>a Web-Developer &amp; Embedded Systems Engineer</whatIAm>
    <technologies>
        <technologies>
            <category>Fullstack</category>
            <tech>
                <tech>java</tech>
            </tech>
        </technologies>
        <technologies>
            <category>Frontend</category>
            <tech>
                <tech>typescript</tech>
                <tech>vite</tech>
                <tech>html</tech>
                <tech>sass</tech>
                <tech>react</tech>
            </tech>
        </technologies>
        <technologies>
            <category>Backend</category>
            <tech>
                <tech>php</tech>
            </tech>
        </technologies>
        <technologies>
            <category>Embedded</category>
            <tech>
                <tech>esp32</tech>
                <tech>arduino</tech>
            </tech>
        </technologies>
        <technologies>
            <category>Tools</category>
            <tech>
                <tech>git</tech>
                <tech>linux</tech>
                <tech>docker</tech>
            </tech>
        </technologies>
    </technologies>
    <motiviation></motiviation>
    <whatILearnCurrently></whatILearnCurrently>
    <texts>
        <intro>
            I’m a developer with a strong interest in building clean,
            interactive, and technically well-structured applications.
            My main focus is modern web development and Java-based
            projects, with an emphasis on performance and maintainability.
        </intro>
        <techStack>
            I primarily work with these technologies:
        </techStack>
        <origin>
            <p>
                I started programming with Fischertechnik at the age of ten. 
                When the COVID pandemic began, my interest deepened further. 
                Since my mother is a teacher and attended various online training 
                sessions, one of which introduced the programming language Java, I 
                followed along out of curiosity. I found the topic fascinating and 
                soon began exploring Java on my own. Over time, this foundation led 
                me to broaden my skill set, and I went on to learn HTML, CSS, JavaScript, 
                and later TypeScript, with a growing focus on web development and interactive applications.
            </p>
        </origin>
        <interests>
            <p>
                I enjoy working on projects where logic and creativity meet.
                This includes canvas-based applications, small games, tools,
                and systems that require thoughtful architecture rather than
                just visual polish.
            </p>
            <p>
                I particularly like projects where I can control the full
                stack or the full rendering pipeline, as it allows me to
                optimize performance and understand every part of the system.
            </p>
        </interests>
        <learning>
            <p>
                I learn primarily by building real projects. Instead of
                following tutorials step by step, I prefer to experiment,
                research problems as they arise, and refine my solutions
                through iteration.
            </p>
            <p>
                I actively explore new technologies, read documentation,
                analyze existing implementations, and apply what I learn
                directly to my own projects.
            </p>
        </learning>
        <goals>
            My goal is to continue growing as a developer by working on
            technically challenging projects and deepening my understanding
            of software architecture, performance optimization, and
            low-level concepts.
        </goals>
    </texts>
</aboutMe>